A box lands on the counter, fifty tubes of the cream.
The one that's been selling, the driver wants a signature, fifty units, he says, count them.
On an old tilt, this is the worst job in the shop. You count all fifty. You match them to the order.
One's missing, recount. The driver's tapping his foot. The line's back,
keen up. And heaven help you if you're off by one because now the whole system is lying.
Ralph doesn't count. He scans one tube just to say this arrived and he's done.
The box is in. He never typed a quantity because here's the thing nobody tells you.
Banko doesn't track how many you have. It tracks what you sell.
The shelf isn't a number in a database. It's the real shelf in the real shop.
And that's slip. The one that says five trays. That's not a stock count.
That's how many labels to print. Five creams, five trays, five labels.
The number on the paper was never about inventory. It was about getting price tags on the shelf.
What about the money? The box costs 120 francs for fifty.
Banko does the math. That's your cost per tube baked right in.
You bought a box. It splits into singles. The margins already there before the first one sells.
So the delivery that used to eat twenty minutes and start an argument.
Ralph logged that. It came and walked away. No count.
No reconcile. No clipboard. Dock to drawer. And nobody counted the thing.
Because you don't count a shop in. You sell it down.
The cream came in quiet. And now it's back on the shelf.
Waiting for Larry, and Sally — and whoever's next.