Half the things in this shop never got a barcode.
Loose herbs, jars, lighters, and a cream that cost 40 francs.
It's Saturday, the new kid's on the till.
A customer wants the 40 franc cream.
She reaches for the scanner out of habit and stops.
There's nothing to scan.
The factory never gave it a barcode.
And on the shelf, five tubes, nearly identical.
One's 40 francs, one's 12, guess wrong?
And the cash drawer never balances.
On an old till, that cream is a price typed by hand,
a sticky note on the monitor, a number she has to remember,
or call the manager again every unmarked item, a tiny gamble.
And the head shop is full of them.
She doesn't scan.
She opens the catalog and there it is,
wearing its own face — a photo, the name, 40 francs.
She taps the picture into the cart, right price, first try.
No sticky notes, no manager.
Because the first time this cream was ever sold,
someone gave it a face, a quick photo at the counter,
born once and from that moment, anyone can sell it by sight.
That's the trick the big chains miss.
A barcode belongs to the factory,
a picture belongs to you, your shelf, your goods, your eyes.
Banco doesn't make you label the world before you sell it.
You sell what you can see.
Born once, known by heart.