One little cream, born on a Friday, rough and nameless,
sold, made proper, restocked, watched from the road,
counted to the franc.
Banco measured all of it, but there's one thing.
The numbers still can't tell us.
Did it actually work?
Was it worth 40 francs?
Only the people who took it home can answer that.
Larry, Sally, the next nervous customer,
holding the tube.
So in season two, we hand them the pen.
Here's how it's going to work.
They never give us an email.
They never do. A first name, maybe an Instagram.
That's enough, because on the receipt
is a little QR code.
They scan it, no app, no password,
and up comes one quick question.
Did it work?
10 seconds, a thumbs-up, a star.
Would you buy it again?
Maybe a photo, a 10-second clip of a calming the bite.
And for their honesty, they are in points, real credit,
toward their next visit.
Those words don't vanish into a database.
They land on the cream itself.
So the next person who hesitates doesn't just see a price.
They see Larry.
They see Sally.
They see it work.
The cream stops selling on Felix's word
and starts selling on the neighborhoods.
And Felix from the road finally sees the whole picture,
not just what sold, but what helped, the velocity,
and the reason behind it.
That's the loop born once, then known,
by the people who carried it home.
We're building it right now, season two of Banco,
where the shop stops talking in the neighborhood starts.
Born once, known forever.