Friday rush, Pam scans something new, a cream, no barcode.
She names it, prises it, snaps a quick photo, sells it, 40 francs done.
It's rough, a fast photo, no details, but the lines moving, and that's the job.
Then Larry buys one, an hour later, Sally buys another, two in a day.
This brand new little cream nobody has heard of on the internet.
They know about today.
Felix isn't in the shop, he's on the road, but he opens his phone and checks the dashboard.
And there it is, selling.
He knows they hit when he sees one.
He also knows the entry is rough.
He can't fix it from the highway, and it's not his job.
So he sends Ralph one text, a link, the creams page on the Artemis website.
Ralph opens that link, beautiful photos, full specs, the whole story, sitting on the website,
a different system, not wired to the till.
So he brings it across by hand, the real photo, the details.
And he checks the one thing that matters, that the barcode Pam scanned really is this product.
Because sometimes it isn't, he confirms it.
Then he sets the cost, a reorder number, the rough little cream just grew up.
Next morning, Pam opens the catalog, and the creams got a new face now.
A real photo, specs that she can read straight to the customer, a margin behind it,
a reorder that won't let it run dry.
Here's the secret, nobody touched the 7,000 products that never sell.
You don't polish a dead shelf, you wait for the shop to sell what's worth it.
And it tells you in sales, a cashier born's it, a manager raises it.
The owner just has to notice, effort follows velocity.