Let me show you something we built
yesterday afternoon.
A full production environment. HTTPS,
OAuth2 login, role-based access control,
six microservices running 24/7
on a dedicated server.
Cost? Seven euros
and 59 cents a month.
Now let me show you what a corporation
takes to do the exact same thing.
This is the Hetzner Cloud console.
That is the server. 2 CPUs, 8 gigs of RAM,
80 gig SSD, 7.59 a month.
Six containers, all healthy.
Caddy for HTTPS, PostgreSQL for database,
Keycloak for identity management,
Redis, RabbitMQ,
and the application itself.
This is a real login. Real Keycloak.
Real OAuth2. Real role-based access control
with five different roles.
This is not a demo. This is not a mockup.
This is production-grade software
running on a seven euro server.
Now here's what a corporation takes
for the same thing. Requirements gathering.
Two weeks, four meetings.
We said: Hetzner, let's go.
Architecture approval.
Three weeks, review board.
We decided on a chat message.
Server provisioning, one to two weeks,
infrastructure ticket.
We clicked the button. 30 seconds.
Docker setup, one week, infrastructure backlog.
We ran one curl command.
TLS certificate. Two weeks,
security team request.
We ran one OpenSSL command.
Total time for a corporation:
eight to 16 weeks. Total budget:
50,000 to 200,000 euros.
We did it in one afternoon.
The difference is not intelligence.
The difference is not tools.
The difference is decision latency.
Corporations spend 90% of their time
asking permission.
We spend 90% of our time building.
When something broke yesterday,
TLS certificates don't work
on bare IP addresses, by the way,
there was no war room.
No post-mortem scheduled for next Tuesday.
We diagnosed it. We fixed it.
And we moved on.
That is not speed.
That is ownership.
Swiss SMEs are paying SAP
50 to 200,000 euros a year
for systems that take six months
to change a form field.
That is not a feature.
That is a trap.
HelixNet is built for the company
with 5 to 50 people
that needs real tools without
the enterprise ransom.
FastAPI. Keycloak. Docker. Open source.
You own it. No license. No lock-in.
If you are a Swiss SME owner asking
why your IT costs more than your rent --
Let's talk. Link in the description.