Midnight, you count the till. It's 40 francs short.
Not a disaster, but 40 francs. And here's the thing that keeps an owner up at night. You have no idea where it went.
A wrong change.
A missed sale. A hand in the drawer.
The old till just shrugs. One drawer. All day, every hand in it.
The money is a blur.
On a shared till, you can't even ask the right question. Three people were today.
The shortfall has no name, no time, no story. So you do what every shop owner does.
You sigh. You eat the 40 francs, and you hope it's less tomorrow.
Banco does it differently. You start your shift by counting your float, your drawer, your number.
From that second, every sale, every paid in, every paid out is tied to you.
Not the till, you. At the end, you count the cash back. And the till tells you
what it should be to the francs. Expect it. Count it. The difference right there.
Now that 40 francs is in a mystery. It's Maria's drawer.
Tuesday, the evening shift. Maybe it's an honest miscount. Maybe it's a coaching moment.
Either way, you can see it. That's not suspicion. That's just light.
You can't fix what you can't see. Banco doesn't accuse anyone. It just counts.
So you never have to wonder again, a drawer that closes because it tells the truth.