Welcome back to the HelixNet Keycloak series. Episode 5 -- RBAC Deep Dive. Last episode we toured the admin console and saw all six realms. Today we go inside the POS realm and look at how role-based access control actually works.
Here are the five custom roles we built for the POS system. Each role has an emoji icon and a clear description. pos-admin -- full system control, the crown. pos-auditor -- read-only access for compliance. pos-cashier -- front-line, limited to 10% discounts. pos-developer -- testing role, no production data. pos-manager -- unlimited discounts and full reporting.
Let's look inside each role. The admin role -- full control over the POS realm and configuration. Notice the tabs: Details, Attributes, Users in role.
The cashier role. Key detail: limited to 10% discount threshold. This is how you prevent staff from giving away the house.
The manager role. Unlimited discounts and reporting. When a customer needs more than 10% off, the manager steps in.
Now click Users in Role to see who has cashier access. This is the other side of the coin -- role to users mapping.
Pam is a front-line cashier. One role: pos-cashier. She can ring up sales and process checkouts. That's it. Principle of least privilege in action.
Ralph has two roles: cashier AND manager. He works the register but can also approve discounts and run reports. This is role accumulation -- each role adds capabilities.
Michael is our developer. One role: pos-developer. He can create test products but has no access to live transactions. Complete separation of concerns.
And Felix. Look at this -- admin, cashier, AND manager. Three roles. Full system control. In a real deployment, you'd have exactly one or two Felix-level users. Everyone else gets the minimum they need.
Client scopes control what information goes into the JWT token. Ten scopes here -- email, profile, roles, web-origins. When a user logs in, these scopes determine what claims appear in their access token.
Seven built-in authentication flows. Browser flow for interactive logins, direct grant for API authentication. Docker auth for container registries, first broker login for federated identity.
The realm settings page. This is mission control. Realm ID: kc-pos-realm-dev. Frontend URL points to our Keycloak instance. SSL required for external requests. OpenID and SAML endpoints at the bottom.
Back to where we started. Five roles, clean RBAC, production-ready. This is what separates a real platform from a toy project. Next episode: client architecture -- how the three POS clients connect to Keycloak.