Check one two, check one two, beginning take five in three seconds. Let me show you
something we built yesterday afternoon, a full production environment, HTTPS, or
two log-in, roll-based access control, six microservices running 24-7 on a
dedicated server. Costs, seven euros, and 59 cents a month. Now let me show you
what a corporation takes to do the exact same thing. This is the Harexner Cloud
console. That is the server. 2CPUs, 8 gigs of RAM, 80 gig SSD, 759 a month, six
containers, all healthy, caddy for HTTPS, Postgres SQL for database, key cloak for
identity management, redis, rabbit MQ, and the application itself. This is a real
log-in, real key cloak, real OAuth 2, real roll-based access control with five
different roles. This is not a demo. This is not a mockup. This is production
grade software running on a seven-year-old server. Now here's what a corporation
takes for the same thing. Requiring requirements gathering. Two weeks, four
meetings, we said, Harexner, let's go. Architectural approval. Three weeks, review
board. We decided on a chat message. Server provisioning one to two weeks
infrastructure ticket. We clicked the button 30 seconds. Docker set up one week
infrastructure backlog. We ran one curl command, TLS certificate. Two weeks
security team request. We ran one open SSL command. Total time for a corporation,
eight to 16 weeks. Total budget, 50,000 to 200,000 euros. We did it in one
afternoon. The difference is not intelligence. The difference is not tools. The
difference is decision latency. Corporations spend 90% of their time asking
permission. We spend 90% of our time building. When something broke yesterday, TLS
certificates don't work on bear IP addresses. By the way, there was no war room,
no post mortem scheduled for next Tuesday. We diagnosed it. We fixed it and we
moved on. That is not speed. That is ownership. Swiss SMEs are paying SAP 50 to
200,000 euros a year for systems that take six months to change a form field.
That is not a feature. That is a trap. Helixnet is built for the company with
five to 50 people that needs real tools without the enterprise, ransom, fast
happy, key cloak, doctor, open source, unit, no license, no lock-in. If you are
Swiss SME owner, asking why your IT costs more than your rent. Let's talk.
Link in the description. That's a take.