20 Years of SAP.
Here's What I'd Build Today.
I've been building SAP integrations
for 20 years.
ABAP proxies for backend lookups,
RFC calls to pull master data in real time.
IDoc and BDoc pipelines
for CRM, logistics, finance.
PI/PO message mappings.
XI before that.
EDI cross-border
for customs and shipping.
I've worked in enterprise integration in Europe.
You probably touched one of the systems I helped build.
Fortune 500. Swiss multinationals.
Cross-border supply chains. I've seen it all.
And I want to be clear.
I'm not here to trash SAP. SAP works.
It solved real problems for real companies.
I built my career on it.
But I'd be lying if I said
the world hasn't changed.
Think about where we were in 2005.
Everything was on-premise.
Every integration was a three to six month project.
You needed a dedicated team just to move data from one system to another.
SAP PI was the answer.
And it was a good answer -- for that world.
But that world is disappearing.
Today you can deploy an integration platform
in an afternoon. Cloud-native. Open source. Containerized.
One person. One laptop.
SAP knows this. That's why they built BTP --
Business Technology Platform.
But migration from PI/PO to BTP is slow, expensive.
And most companies I talk to -- they're stuck in the middle.
Running PI/PO because it works,
knowing it won't last forever, not sure what comes next.
So let me show you what I built today --
if I were starting fresh.
This is HelixNet. A production platform
I built using only open source tools.
FastAPI for the backend.
Modern Python, async, automatic API documentation.
This right here -- this is what PI/PO message mappings does.
Except it's 10 lines of Python instead of a visual mapper that takes days to configure.
Keycloak. Enterprise identity management.
OAuth2. OpenID Connect. Role-based access control.
This is what SAP Access Control charges
hundreds of thousands of euros for. It's open source. It's free.
Six microservices, all containerized.
Deploy anywhere, running right now on a dedicated server.
Cost? Seven euros and 59 cents.
Per month.
Now here's the thing. I'm not saying tear out SAP tomorrow.
That would be reckless.
And I've seen enough reckless migrations
to know how that ends.
But if you're planning what comes after PI/PO --
and you should be -- you need someone who understands both sides.
Someone who can read an IDoc
and write a REST API.
Someone who knows why your RFC calls work today
and why they won't scale tomorrow.
Someone who spent 20 years inside the SAP world
and the last six months building what comes next.
The future is hybrid.
SAP alongside open source.
Legacy alongside modern.
And hybrid needs a translator.
That's what I do.
I'm the bridge.
If your company is somewhere in the middle ground --
running SAP but wondering what's next -- I'd like to talk.
Not to sell you anything.
Just to show what's possible.
20 years taught me how enterprise works.
The last six months taught me how fast it can be.
The link is below.