So, what I've been saying for a while
now is finally coming true. And what
we're seeing around the world is what's
called the end of globalization.
>> Globalization
has failed the West [music] and the
United States of America.
The world has changed much and I believe
the progress that we have made in the
partnership
sets us up well for the new world order.
Okay, so what does that mean? Well,
here's a very simple way of looking at
it. After World War II, the world came
to an agreement about how to structure
the new world order. China became the
factory of the world. Japan became the
lender by keeping rates at zero, keeping
the system liquid. Europe became the
buyer and consumer of the world. They
traded productivity and military for
stability and social welfare. And the
United States became the country that
enforced the whole thing with the petro
dollar as the world's reserve currency
backed by the military-industrial
complex. Now that system is what Simon
Dixon coined as the proof of weapons
network which means if countries want to
trade or if they want money to build
their economies they have to agree to
the rules. The rules were use dollars to
buy energy and do not mess with US
interests. The petro dollar made sure
that the world needed dollars to buy its
energy. The military enforced it all and
financial institutions along with the
central banks managed the flow of all
this money. So if you play by the rules,
you got access to investment markets and
protection. And if you broke the rules,
you got punished with things like
sanctions or just outright war. Now, if
you're an American, depending on which
side of the K-shaped economy you were
on, rich or poor, then you indirectly
benefited from that system because US
companies made a lot of money. And if
you were an investor, you also made a
lot of money and you got to retire
happy. The downside though was that to
keep this system going, it doesn't just
take a war, it takes a forever war,
which is bad for the world. Now, if
you're poor as an American, it's
especially bad because the system gave
out all the jobs. Supply chains left,
factories left, and what it did was it
concentrated wealth. It hollowed out the
middle class, and it created a very
fragile dependency on other nations for
their stuff. Cuz America stopped making
stuff. The only thing America made was
money and technology. And for a long
time, that's how the world worked.
Technically, it still does. at least on
paper, but it's coming to the end
because fast forward to today and some
of these nations decided to team up and
said, "Okay, we'll make our own system
then." And they've become so powerful at
this point that the proof of weapons
network cannot enforce the rules anymore
without going to World War II, which no
one wants. And at the most recent
meeting at the World Economic Forum in
Switzerland, which just happened, the
people who sort of control these levers
of power, said that this game is over.
>> Globalization
has failed the West and the United
States of America. It's a failed policy.
It is what the W has stood for which is
export
offshore farshore find the cheapest
labor in the world and the world is a
better place for it. The fact is it has
left America behind. It has left the
American workers behind.
>> So now Japan is being forced to
repatriate its capital back, sell their
US treasuries just like all the other
nations in this new world. This weakens
the dollar because the dollar needs
perpetual demand and that demand is
disappearing. Europe learned [music] if
you depend on other countries for your
energy and you outsource your safety and
your military, well then you've got no
power to enforce the rules. So what
we're left with is what was talked about
at this World Economic Forum. The
question was, how do we divide power in
this new world order? That's what I want
to help explain. I want to show you who
the players are, what each of them
wants, and what it might look like in
the future. So, with that said, let's
get into it. Hi, my name is Andre Jick.
Hope you're doing well. Come for the
finance and stay for the new world
order. So, the old game that's been
played since World War II for about 80
years or so is coming to an end. And it
kind of perfectly lines up with
something called the fourth turning,
which is a model that shows that every
20 years we've got a new cycle which
starts with the high followed by the
awakening, then the unraveling, and now
the crisis or the reset. That's where
the World Economic Forum in Davos,
Switzerland, comes in. This is where the
world's most powerful people get
together to talk about what the new game
is going to look like. This is the
largest gathering of global leadership
of the postcoid period of time.
>> So, first I'm going to try to explain
who the players are and what they want.
This gets very complex. There's all
kinds of different power structures with
different incentives, pulling in all
different directions, all trying to take
a piece of whatever replaces this old
system. So, let me give you a high-level
condensed overview of what's happening.
Now there are technically four groups of
power. The first group is what we can
call the financial globalists. Some
people call it the transnational
capital. Why is it called that? It's
called that because transnational
capital means these people do not pledge
allegiance to a flag. They don't
represent a nation's interests. They are
money and money can be anywhere. Hence,
transnational because it transcends
nations. So, who are these people? Who
am I talking about? Well, at the very
top, these are the asset managers. And
at the top of that food chain are three
specific ones. They're the apex
predators of this structure. And that is
Black Rockck, Vanguard, and State
Street, which together manage tens of
trillions of dollars. Now they thrive in
a world where money or capital can move
anywhere, any place, any time. Now that
money is not their money obviously, it's
their client's money. But with that
money, they are given a superpower.
That superpower is that all corporations
around the world become subordinate to
them. How? Well, because corporations
optimize for access to capital or money.
And through that, asset managers get to
vote on behalf of their shareholders.
And here's an example of what I mean,
cuz I know it sounds confusing. If
you're buying mutual funds or ETFs at a
place like Black Rockck, your money is
being allocated to different types of
funds, but you don't get to vote on what
the individual companies within those
funds get to do. Now, you can vote with
some funds, but the reality is this
chart right here is that most people
won't even bother at all. And this chart
right here is from Black Rockck's
website, which actually shows that in
2025, out of the 7.4 trillion in total
index equity, only 3.65 trillion was
even eligible for voting. But of that,
only 812 billion actually voted. That's
only 11% of total index equity, which
means 89% of their clients votes was
exercised by Black Rockck, not by their
clients. So even though asset managers
don't own the money they manage, they
are using their clients money to vote
which way a company goes and who those
companies hire for their members of the
board. Now downstream from that is
everything else like access to capital,
access to markets and all the other
things. That's why Larry Frink is at the
top of this food chain. He is the top G
here. And what you have to understand
about this power structure is that it it
does not need to pass laws or control
the military because by controlling
capital flows, they're able to guide
most of the decisions because if you're
the CEO of a company and the money flows
to you, well then your company grows.
But if it leaves and you get kicked out
of the index, well then your company
gets smaller and you get fired. So if
you want to succeed, then you're going
to probably do as you're told, and that
is the ultimate superpower. Now, I
should also mention though that there's
not just one apex predator here. There's
another one, and that's the banks and
the Federal Reserve. So asset managers
and banks, I believe, are separate
players with their own unique interests.
And I think you can tell that from this
conversation between Larry Frink and
Christine Lagarde where she drops a hint
that central banks might not always be
around.
>> So I'm not going to tell you that there
is a red line. I'm not going to tell you
that central banks will always be around
either.
>> Speak to what you did. You just said
something very interesting.
>> I'm not going to speak more to it.
>> No. To this [laughter]
to no to the idea that central banks
might not always be around. What did you
mean by that? Look, I went through uh my
lot of crisis as many of you have as
well. And I remember the days when it
was mentioned that you know central
bankers are the only game in town. This
is not the right approach to a balanced
and durable equilibrium.
>> Okay. So asset managers are separate
from the banks which are competing
together. Now on the bank side, the apex
predator here is Jamie Diamond of JP
Morgan Chase and he says he's a
globalist.
>> You know, hey, ready? You can. Here's
your headline. I'm a globalist.
>> Now, a globalist means if it were up to
him, he would continue the world order
as it is today. He wants NATO to be
strong. He wants to protect the
interests of the West. And he wouldn't
change much.
>> I want a stronger NATO, a stronger
Europe. Some of the things Trump has
done are causing that, some are not. I'm
not a tariff guy, though I'd use it in
the cases I had. I think they should
change their approach to immigration.
I've said it. What the hell else do you
want me to say? So the central banks are
resisting all of this, which kind of
makes sense because they're the power
structure that benefited the most from
it. So asset managers and banks, two
different players that want two
different things, but both are part of
the same power structure, which Simon
Dixon coined as FIC or the financial
industrial complex. The second group of
power players are what you might call
the sovereigns, right? And these are the
leaders of tier one nations. Tier one
meaning those with access to nuclear
weapons. Now, a sovereign is someone
that believes globalization is a threat
to their power and control. A sovereign
is not necessarily trying to win the
globalization game. They're just trying
not to lose control. And their power
comes from things like laws, borders,
tariffs, and sometimes they're even
willing to sacrifice their market for
their sovereignty, their independence.
and they're willing to put up with some
economic pain not to lose control over
industry, energy, and security. Now, who
are they specifically, right? Well, that
might be someone like Vladimir Putin,
right? A guy who doesn't want to
privatize his nation's resources. He
doesn't care if Russia's stock market
isn't doing all that great. He wants it
so that only the Russian government can
drill for his oil and not Exon Mobile or
Chevron. He doesn't really care if
Russian stocks underperform US markets.
And sovereigns also don't care if the
rest of the world doesn't really want to
play with them, right? Same can be said
of China's Xi Jinping. He prefers state
control and long-term growth over access
to Western capital. Same can also be
said of North Korea's Kim Jong-un. Same
same but different. Sovereign power
resists globalization cuz they know they
cannot win this game. And that's also
why the financial industrial complex
hates them so much because they're
unpredictable and they are inefficient
from a capital point of view. But
they're popular and their voters keep
choosing them because they promise
control and obedience. They have clean
streets, right? They have order which is
very efficient. So their people really
love them. So in a nutshell they
understand that to allow transnational
capital in their countries would mean
giving up all the leverage that they
have. Now the third group are the
technologists sometimes called the
technocrats and they don't really care
about nationalism versus globalism. They
mostly care about things like
efficiency, scale and networks. They
believe that technology will someday
replace or automate a lot of what
governments and institutions are doing
right now. But I also think it's
important to understand that
technologists are not necessarily at the
top of the power structure. They don't
control the capital flows. They can work
with almost any player in the system as
long as they are given funding, access
to data, and the permission. Right? In
that sense, they're also transnational
because their software goes beyond their
borders. And as globalization breaks
down, they kind of get more powerful,
right? How? Well, because financial
power pushes for programmable money,
digital IDs, social credit scores,
automation, robots, etc. Right? So, the
capital moves in their direction and
they get more powerful. They have a lot
of leverage but they're not quite the
most powerful as the financial players
are in this structure. Now then there's
the fourth group though which is the
military-industrial complex and this is
sort of like the enforcement layer.
Their power comes from force and the
intelligence agencies. They thrive
mostly on instability and their role is
just to enforce whatever system is in
place right now. They're not really
subordinate to the government like you
might think. They're more subordinate to
the financial industrial complex because
it's the financial powers that dominate
the government, not the other way
around. Okay. So, now that you hopefully
understand who the players are, the next
question is what do they actually want?
So, let me start with the most powerful
group of them all, which is the
financial industrial complex. Now, one
of those players, the asset managers,
what they want is a world where money or
capital stays liquid, fast, and
controllable even if nations and
countries fragment, right? Because
delobalization is a problem for them
because borders slow money down.
Different countries have different
rules, [music] different currencies,
different settlement systems. And all of
that is what's called friction. It adds
cost and complexity and all the stuff
they don't want to deal with. So their
solution then is tokenization and
fractionalization, which is something
Larry Frink has talked about for years.
[music]
>> I think the movement towards uh
tokenization, decimalization
is is necessary. I think we need to move
very rapidly u uh to doing that. We
would be reducing fees. We would do more
democratization.
>> Now tokenization just means taking
assets like stocks, bonds, real estate,
commodities, whatever and putting them
on a blockchain so they can trade
instantly globally 24/7. And
fractionalization means breaking those
assets into smaller pieces so that more
people can own them and they can move
them faster. So now you can live
anywhere in the world and regardless of
which country you come from, anyone can
buy stocks from anywhere in the world,
right? But what that also does in
practice is that it hugely benefits
whoever controls the rails now. Asset
managers already control the assets, but
tokenization
allows them to control the
infrastructure as well. And in the
future, AI is going to play a huge role
in managing this whole system. And
because it's on the blockchain rail,
they're going to have all the tools in
the world to see everything that's
happening in real time. And they'll be
able to take advantage of that
information for better or for worse. But
remember, there's also the bankers. And
what do the banks want? Well, preferably
to kind of keep it all the same. But
really their biggest goal right now is
to avoid the privatization of money.
Here's one of the central bankers at
Davos saying exactly this.
>> As I am a central banker, let me insist
a bit on at least I I gave a speech two
weeks ago with a triangle of threats and
a triangle of answer. But let me sum up.
The first threat is privatization of
money. So in other words, they want to
not be what's called disintermediated,
meaning they don't want to be cut out of
the capital flows. They don't want to be
made irrelevant. How do they do that?
>> Here's the answer is CBDC.
central bank digital currencies, CBDC's.
This is how the old system is trying to
stay relevant because if cash is
disappearing, if private payment rails
are taking over, if tokenized assets are
routing around them and asset managers
are building this new infrastructure
without the banks, well, that shrinks
the power of the banks. So CBDC's are a
way for the central banks to have their
own programmable money and banks have to
be very careful here because if
corporate CBDC's are allowed to exist
and if they pay an interest or a yield
that threatens banks deposits, banks
don't want their deposit money leaving
because their customers are buying
corporateissued digital currencies like
Tesla coin that's going to pay them a 5%
yearly interest on their savings instead
of their savings account that's going to
pay them 0.2% interest, right? That's an
existential threat to the banking power.
So, just remember that the banks want
CBDC's and control over what
corporations can and can't do with them.
But they also have some competition and
their biggest competitor is the crypto
lobby. Now, the crypto lobby is
challenging the banks and what the
crypto people want is fair competition
because in a fair game, crypto wins.
Crypto knows that and the banks know
that. And here's the CEO of the biggest
crypto company in the US saying exactly
what I just said.
>> I think Americans should be able to earn
more money on their money. Uh banks
should have to compete on a level
playing field and if the American people
feel like the banks are not paying high
enough interest rates and stable coin
rewards can offer them more then maybe
the banks should have to pay higher
interest rates to compete. Right?
>> So that was Brian Armstrong and he wants
to make sure that the rules are such
that the crypto lobby can compete with
the banking lobby. Crypto people want
control over the CBDC's so they could
pay you a higher interest rate for
holding your cash with them which
ultimately threatens what the bank
deposits which is the bank's source of
power. But guess who's got more money,
more lawyers, and more influence. That
would be the banks, which is why the
crypto lobby is upset right now because
the legislation is not fair to them cuz
obviously it's not designed to be and
that's how the game is played. So
anyway, at the very top, we've got the
asset managers, then the banks, then the
crypto powers, which depending on how
regulation goes in the future, aka who
has the bigger wallet for the
politicians, this might flip and the
crypto lobby could someday overtake the
banks. So that's the financial
industrial complex or the FIC structure.
That's power player number one. Power
player number two are the sovereigns.
Now, what do the sovereigns want? And
what they want is almost the opposite,
right? They care about a seat at this
table and control of their resources.
Their ideal world is where they control
their energy, their food, their
industry, their security, even if that
means slower growth and slower markets,
right? Some countries just want to be
left alone. Other countries want to
consolidate power regionally and absorb
their geographic proxies like Russia
wants to do with Ukraine, like China
with Taiwan, like the US did with
Venezuela and Greenland and whatever
else, right? And some of these countries
have expansionary dreams, right? They
want to have a seat at the table, which
is why Russia says they're going to join
Trump's board of peace and they'll pay a
billion dollars if they could use the
money that the US froze from Russia and
if they could help broker the deal in
Palestine because they want to be a part
of it.
>> Okay. Well, then you have the
technologists and they don't really care
who's in charge politically. What they
want are the government contracts, the
data, and maybe a bailout if that's what
keeps them spending. And in return,
they'll develop all the things like
digital IDs, the robots, the social
credit scores, and and they'll trade the
data and the tech with whichever faction
happens to be in power. And then there's
the military-industrial complex. They
weren't super represented at the World
Economic Forum, but their interests are
usually instability, which justifies
spending, which enriches the defense
contractors, which is ultimately a proxy
for the financial industrial complex.
Now, the good news, though, is this. If
all goes well, the world should not be
going to World War II. Instead, we
should hopefully see less invasion and
less occupation because the forever war
model is unwinding. So, in a nutshell,
asset managers want programmable money.
The crypto people want to have
competition. The banks want to not be
irrelevant. Sovereigns want control over
their own countries without being
destabilized while having a seat at the
table. Technologists want access to
money. And the military is there to just
enforce the rules. Now, a lot of what I
said is overly simplified in this video,
but it is based on provable information.
But really, the most important takeaway
from this video is that I'm not
describing altruism versus evil or good
versus bad. This is just power versus
power. And there's a lot that I don't
want to say, not cuz I'm not allowed to,
but because I don't want to sound like a
conspiracy theorist. But if I could just
give you my personal opinion about all
of it, I think that all of this has
already been negotiated. And what we're
watching is just political theater. What
we're seeing in Venezuela and Greenland
and Russia, it's just theater to justify
it all. It's geopolitical posturing for
the countries. They're like, "Okay, in
this new game, how do I want to be
perceived? Am I weak? Am I strong? Who
am I?" Right? What is my identity here?
[snorts] That is the theater. And this
is the algorithms making us engage in
all of it. But the reality is that the
range of possible outcomes for all these
possible futures has already been
pre-negotiated. Maybe not the exact
script, but the general big idea, I
think, has already been established. But
hey, in the meantime, enjoy the
celebration andor the humiliation of
certain people. I can't prove it, but
that's just my theory. Now, I do want to
give credit because some of this
framework was borrowed from Simon Dixon,
who's not only talked about this for
years, but has made a lot of videos
about these topics. And if you're
interested in this sort of stuff, I'd
recommend to check out his YouTube
channel because it is a rabbit hole that
you will not be coming out of. The link
is down below. In the meantime, I'd love
to hear your thoughts about all of this.
I hope you have a wonderful rest of your
day. Smash the like button, subscribe if
you haven't already. I'd love to see you
back here next week. I'll see you soon.
Bye-bye.