Welcome back. This is a little explanation of what zero perpetual inventory means.
Big companies, they have systems like SAP, ERP, MRP, materials, resource planning, for example.
And they keep what you call a perpetual inventory, a running count of every unit.
Now this is great for a warehouse with a hundred SKUs that never change.
It's useless for a kiosk or a head shop with a thousand products.
New stuff weekly, half of it unbarcoded, old stock piling up.
There the count is wrong, the moment you write it down.
A wrong number is worse than no number.
So, Banco, the Helix POS that we are going to demonstrate here, does the opposite.
Zero perpetual inventory.
Don't count. Learn the shop by watching what sells.
Always true, it actually happened.
Every item is born once, the first time, you meet it, then known forever.
The catalog builds itself.
The question MRP exists to answer, what do I re-buy?
We answer from velocity, not a count nobody keeps honest.
And that's a take there.