Here's the question that wakes up every shop owner at three in the morning.
What's happening in my shop right now when I'm not standing in it?
Felix owns Artemis, but he's almost never behind the counter.
He's on the road between a hundred other things.
So how does he sleep at night?
He opens his phone.
Thirty seconds, today's sales.
Who's on the till?
That's Pam.
The drawer.
Counted and balanced.
And the cream from yesterday's delivery.
Selling down, tube by tube.
Exactly like it should.
He's two hundred kilometers away.
He can watch his shop breathing.
And that little badge in the corner, PRD, tells him he's in the real shop live.
Not a test, not yesterday.
The numbers are now.
He's not guessing.
And he's not calling in to interrupt Pam mid sale.
He just knows.
If something's off, he catches it from the highway and sends one text.
If everything's fine, he closes the phone and keeps driving.
Either way, the shop didn't need him standing inside it to be safe.
That's the freedom nobody sells you with a cash register.
The freedom to not be there.
A shop that runs while you're gone —
because the watching is built in.
Felix can finally leave the shop and still have it.