We sold a product that didn't exist.
Watch a cashier scans something brand new, names it,
prices it, snaps a photo, sells it,
The receipt prints. The points land.
the customer walks out happy. Everything looks perfect.
Two minutes later she goes to ring up another one.
She searches the name. Nothing, no matches.
The product she just made and sold is gone.
The sale was real, the money was real, the points were real,
but the product never saved, never in the catalog.
It vanished the second the receipt printed. A phantom.
Now imagine that's your shop. Every new barcode a cashier scans sold once
then gone. A catalog full of holes. The one
promised this whole thing makes scan once,
known forever, silently broken, and nobody notices
because the sale never fails.
So we hunted it. There are two ways to make a product.
One, let the cashier straight through. It's twin.
The one that fires when you scan a fresh barcode, slam the door.
A permission error, swallowed in silence. One seal worked.
The identical seal right next to it
leaked. We found it. One line. We sent the barcode through
the same door. The cashier was already allowed through.
And now she scans, creates, sells, searches.
There it is. It's stuck forever. Found on a phone,
killed before ever touched a real shop because if one seal fails,
you check all the seals. That's the difference between software that's
tested and the software that has been lived in.